and then use those APIs to move to
physically move the camera.
>> How easy is that, man? You're just like
move the camera and then you wait and
all of a sudden it goes you're like oh
like
>> best part of acting when you can just
you know critical think.
Yeah, dude.
All right, hackers. If you're really
looking to take the deep dive this year,
I really recommend you check out the
critical thinkers tier in the CTV
Discord. Okay, this is the place where
we are doing hackalongs, AMAs, giving
you exclusive content that only the
inner circle has access to to boost you
as a hacker. Master classes, um you
know, custom interviews with uh extended
interviews with guests, that sort of
thing. It's a great way to support the
pod and it's a great way to invest in
yourself as a hacker and it's a tax
write off for sure. So give it a shot.
Check it out. ctv.show/isord.
We'll hope you join us. Thanks.
Hey, what's up y'all? Um, welcome back
to Critical Thinking. Today we have one
of our dear friends and in my opinion,
uh, one of the greatest experts from a
hardware hacking perspective, uh, Mr.
Matt Brown.
Uh,
>> I want to give him a round of applause
right here for you.
>> Exactly. And uh in in uh normal fashion
as Justin likes to do, we'll start
straight with the bug. So why don't you
give us a cool bug?
>> All right. Thank you guys for having me
on the pod. Uh it's good to be back. Uh
yeah, so uh this bug I wanted to share
is uh is one that I found in let's just
say an industrial uh control system. Uh
a little bit more less uh consumerf
facing uh business facing kind of a
target. And so, uh, this, uh, piece of
hardware that I got sent to, uh, do some
bug bounty hunting on, uh, was, uh,
effectively a device that allowed you to
remotely view the controls of this, you
know, very large, uh, expensive
industrial control system. And so, uh,
there was this protocol, uh, in it that
would, uh, would reach out to the to the
internet from the device. And so, uh,
the first thing I do, uh, on any any
kind of device that's communicating over
the network, I'm an old school like
network wire guy. So, I love to, uh,
open up Wireshark, uh, monitor all the
traffic that's going on, uh, between the
device and the internet. And, uh, I was
seeing, uh, yeah, some interesting, uh,
UDP data. So a lot of times uh maybe in
the in the web hacking world you're used
to just uh you're kind of you know
standard you know IP TCP you know you're
probably got TLS and then on and then
inside of that TLS session is HTTP. Well
in the IoT world you get a lot of like
custom uh rolled UDP protocols. And so I
was actually seeing some uh some clear
text data kind of going through that
stream that gave me some intelligence.
uh let's just say it gave me some uh
some information about uh this device
and a session ID and then I started
poking into the mobile app. So, I always
like to like to go down multiple avenues
uh for these IoT targets. And often
times there's some kind of a mobile app
or maybe a thick client that will
interact with the cloud and uh kind of
sync data down. And so I started uh
digging into the mobile app, did uh kind
of the standard unpinning. So I I I got
Freda in there, modified the app, and uh
got it unpinned so I could see the web
traffic from the from the mobile app.
And I found there was this, let's just
say a a a a incremental uh session token
that was more or less being used to uh
to connect to this remote session to
remotely view this this piece of
industrial uh equipment, right?
>> Holy crap.
>> And it wasn't exactly a Unix time stamp,
right? So there was some part,
you know, you know, it it was close to
that, but
>> it wasn't exactly a Unix time stamp.
Well, well, it didn't line up with the
exact date, right? But you could see
that it was incrementing at the level of
like a mill like like the integer was
incrementing at the millisecond kind of
level or the second level. I forget it
as well.
>> Matt, they changed. It wasn't it wasn't
actual Unix epoch. They added a few days
to it, you know.
>> That's pretty much encryption in my
book, you know.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Well, yeah. And and
especially in the hardware and IoT world
when you start to dig in some of these
devices, the the security model is like
obscurity, right? security through
obscurity sometimes. So um so when I had
my device, I was able to initiate a
session and I was able to see that
session ID of my device. And what was
also interesting is that the whole fleet
kind of operated on the same incremental
like like the server side was handing
out the session token. Uh, and so I was
able to just initiate a session on my
device and then either go, you know,
walk backwards or forwards from that
session ID and I was able to uh remotely
connect to other remote sessions uh uh
and and monitor other people's uh
industrial control systems. So
>> that is nuts. Like I mean we we've all
heard of like incremental IDOR. Yeah,
>> not going to lie, incremental session
token is one that I haven't heard
before. That's nuts.
>> And you didn't even call it out as a bug
there because obviously it takes man in
the middle, but they were also in plain
text, right, on UDP.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. That part was uh
kind of wrapped up in uh let's just say
another finding that I that I reported
and and uh and and that that that ended
up being a dupe. And yeah, there there's
a whole there's a whole bunch of uh
stuff that happened with the result of
this uh find. Well, I I kind of wanted
to ask about that. So, I mean, this is a
hardware boat bounty. They sent you the
the the hardware device, right? Yes. You
start hacking on it. Um,
>> what are the what are the bounties like?
How do they how did they compared to
web?
>> Uh, yeah, they they were significantly
better than uh their kind of standard
program. So, this this target had uh a
public program and I find this is the
case a lot of times. There's like a
public program and then they have a
private hardware program. And I would
say the bugs were uh about 3x uh
whatever
>> the categories of the web of the web
was.
>> That's what I like to see. You know, we
were talking about this a little bit
before the episode before we started,
you know, recording, but like there
there have been some programs out there
where they're like throw a hardware
device at us and they're like, you know,
it's either like 1x their normal
bounties, right? So just their normal
bounties or sometimes even lower. And
I'm like, guys, no. like I'm not going
to you don't understand how much time
this takes, you know. Um so it is good
to see a little bit of a multiple there
where you get a premium for that unique
skill set.
>> Why don't you uh now that we're past the
first bug, why don't you intro Matt for
us?
>> Okay. All right. All right, guys. You
guys know Matt, we we did an episode
with Matt in the past, but if you if you
haven't caught that one, Matt Brown is
like I don't know, man. I I'll I'll tell
a little backstory here as well. Well,
Matt lives close to me uh in the United
States and we met up and I was trying to
get him a while back to like join the
critical thinking brand because I love
his product so much. His hardware
hacking videos are unbelievable. They've
been taken off on YouTube left and
right. Um they are just the kind of
technical, you know, quality content
that we love here at Critical Thinking
where you're actually getting down in
the weeds of it. Um talking about the
the the details and and I I don't know.
I guess as somebody who considers myself
like you know intermediate beginner
intermediate in hardware hacking like
the the stuff is advanced where I'm I'm
learning a lot but it's approachable
enough uh to help me grow you know um so
it's really really good and that I mean
that is a very hard you know needle to
thread there in my opinion like being
approachable but also like clearly you
know advanced. Um, so I I love Matt's uh
Matt's hardware stuff and yeah, he's
he's been doing some um you know, some
work penetration testing off the back of
that and uh and yeah, I don't know, man.
I guess I just we just vibe. So, uh I
love to have you on the podcast to talk
about um hardware hacking stuff and that
last episode we did was one of my
favorites that we've recorded.
>> Well, thanks. Yeah, it's good to good to
be on again.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. So, I um you know, the main vision
or goal for this episode, I think that
uh the reason why I was so excited to
have Matt on is we have just seen since
he was on last a huge explosion of
humanoid robots, right? You know,
they're not in everybody's home yet, but
you see marketing material for them
literally everywhere on every social
media platform. People are talking about
it. There's like the little creepy one
with like the weird eyes that came out
recently. There's already been multiple
like take over every robot vulnerability
found. And I think that there's
something from like a security research
perspective that is much more visceral
when it comes to a hardware device in
your home. You know, I think Justin on
the Halloween episode had an insane
hardware related finding where, you
know, a device could be listening to you
in your home. But it gets even more
real. I mean, obviously having like an
iRoot vacuum that's like spying on you
and going room to room is like also
pretty intense, but a a robot that can
actually harm you that actually has the
ability to like physically harm you or
steal your things or break your things
if someone were to take over it feels
real in a way that um nothing else does,
right? I don't maybe it's because
there's movies like iRoot or whatever
that that have come out. But anyways, I
want to get Matt on because I think that
like just the idea of hacking the robots
of the future is like such um a crazy
and a cool idea and um and then you know
there's there's already a huge
discussion to be had around um hardware
bug bounty hacking and then personally
you know I'm like really interested in
AI in general and so I wanted to talk to
them about like two things. We're gonna
get to all these topics, but the one is,
you know, can you and how would you use
AI to assist hardware hacking? And then
kind of the other thing is like if if a
person was just like getting into bug
bounty uh for hardware because I think
that hardware hacking is going to be
more resilient to, you know, the hackbot
takeover or whatever. I'm actually more
optimistic about this, but we'll get we
can get into it later. But if someone
wanted to get into hardware um hacking,
you know, how would they do it? Um and I
know that's a common question for you,
Matt, so I'm excited to hear all those
answers. Um but yeah, let's let's let's
start with um you know where you and
Justin were already at. Like how do you
kind of see the hardware bug bounty
scene? Is it like better than it's ever
been? Has it been like kind of
declining? Like how do you has it is it
growing? Um and you know have there been
some that you've seen that have like
already incorporated AI into some of
their hardware devices or not? Are you
getting asked about that for your cold
reachouts?
Yeah. So,
the hardware bug bounty scene is uh an
interesting beast, I would say. Uh and
and I think there's some things that are
aligned with the general bug bounty
scene in that program selection is
really important, right? You guys have
experienced this. you you know it's it's
always a risk to invest time into a new
program because you don't know how they
operate, if they're going to take your
findings seriously, if they're going to
short change you or just downgrade
severity because they have budget issues
or something like that. So, I think
there's just more risk in that in the in
the hardware scene because like you
said, there's a lot of initial time
investment that you're going to put into
a hardware hacking target. And so, uh if
you land if you roll the dice on a bad
program, you're going to find out later
on down the line
>> that that they're not a good fit, right?
So, there are uh but there but there are
there are good hardware book bounty
programs out there. there's not as many
public ones is what I've experienced.
So, unfortunately, you have to kind of
dip your toe in the water uh with one of
them. And then once once you get a
couple findings under your belt, you're
going to get those those private
invites, which is really helpful in the
hardware scene because sometimes there
are private programs out there that have
a device that you can't even go buy
online, right? it it it might be a a B2B
type of a a device that you can't just
you can't just go on Amazon and buy this
thing, right? Um obviously for consumerf
facing devices you can do that and if
it's a public program um but I I do
think that uh there is an advantage uh
to hardware bug bounty where some of
these public programs if you get one
finding uh especially on a specific
program you might instantly get invited
to a private event a private uh program.
>> Wow. Uh that's pretty cool. where
whereas whereas in the web scene, I
think you have to grind a lot more to to
get those invites like to live hacking
events and things like that. So, I've
talked to some people, they submitted
one bug, it was a good bug, and then
they got invited to an event because it
was a hardware target. So,
>> that's awesome. Have you do you have any
public programs that you want to shout
out for the hardware hacking world that
you've had good experiences with?
>> Yeah, I mean I mean Amazon. So uh their
their their program is public. I mean
they have they have Yeah. So they have
>> the thing that impresses me about
Amazon's program is that their
description of severity is very well
defined and there's a cutout for
hardware. So they define the severity
very specifically for their hardware
targets that matches their threat model.
So you guys have talked about this on
the pod before. When you're interacting
with a program, you want to figure out
what matters to them, right? Uh but
sometimes if you're if it's if you're
new to a program and they don't tell you
what their threat model is, you just
have to guess and submit bugs and then
you get like you think it's a high, they
come back and they're like, "That's a
low. We've got compensating controls. We
don't really that's not in our threat
model." And you have to kind of almost
like test the target uh to see what
their threat model is. And the thing I
appreciate about appreciate about Amazon
and I would encourage anyone who's
building a hardware bug bounty program
is to just have like it's it's just a
simple little paragraph that they have
for this is severity, this or this is a
critical, these are the kinds of very
hardware specific findings that would
fall into that category. and then
layering down from there in the other
severity categories. So, that's so
helpful because there's just not like
you get into a situation where there's
uh unmet expectations, right? And so, uh
like we said with hardware, it just
takes longer for you to figure out that
those expectations aren't aligned if
you're going in blind. So,
>> yeah, that's scary, man. That's scary
for normal bug bounty hunters, right?
But it's worse for hardware hackers
because there's so much upfront
investment. It's good to hear that you
vouch for the Amazon program because
they have a lot of devices, too. I've
also had a really good experience with
Amazon hardware hacking program. Um, so
that seems like a good place for people
to start at if they're uh if they're
looking to kick off.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. On that bug bounty metagame point,
um, I think one thing that's worth
stating is that the the platforms will
real will like learn that you're a
hardware hacker as well. And in fact, in
the platforms, you can go tag that. So,
a lot of times if you go edit your
profile in like Hacker One or or Bug
Crowd or what have you, you can go in
there and set like, oh, I have an
expertise or an interest in hardware
hacking. Please send me hardware hacking
invites. And then I think like you said,
once you submit a couple, the platform
program owners, you know, the the the
people at Hacker One or Bug Crowd or
Yes, We Hack or whatever, we'll see that
you have an interest in this and you can
actually find real vaults and then
they'll start giving you those invites.
So, I think that's a really really
clutch recommendation.
Yeah, I did want to circle back around
to one of those rapidfire questions that
Reszo shot at you in the beginning,
which was the um the AI on hardware
devices stuff. Have you run into any of
that? And uh you know, do you have any
nuance about threat models or anything
that's different in that world?
>> So, I haven't run into any of that in a
bug bounty target. I've I've run into
some of those systems uh professionally
in private pentest that I can't I can't
I can't get into obviously but I can say
generally about the IoT and hardware
industry there's some really interesting
things happening so even before the LLM
boom let's call it there was a push to
get machine learning uh think especially
in security camera context right you
have your doorbell you want your
doorbell to identify if a person is
coming up to your front door and you
want to get a push notification maybe
with like a thumbnail, right? A clip and
you want it to do the AI to,
>> you know, you don't want just motion
detection. You don't want just like some
leaves blow by your door uh to trigger
this alert, right? And so I would say
phase one of machine learning on
hardware was the the doorbell, the
camera, the the whatever the thing would
send all that data back to the cloud and
they'd have a data center like with
servers with Nvidia GPUs uh in it and
they would do all of their the heavy
lift uh on the back end and then they
would send the push notification. And
what people don't like about that is it
takes time, right? Uh for if if
somebody's approaching my property, I
like seconds matter, right? Like in in a
kind of physical security context or uh
or some other context like that. And so
phase two has been to bring AI to the
edge on the hardware, right? And so now
you're seeing platforms like the Nvidia
Jetson that bring uh kind of GPU or or
you have Google's like TPU tensor uh
processing units that bring uh ML
acceleration to hardware on the edge
that's low power, right? That stuff in
the data center. They don't they don't
really care about uh you know conserving
power like it's not running on battery
in the data center. But you have these
devices now that are running all those
algorithms locally. And what I think
you're going to see, and I've already
seen some of this, is you're starting to
see LLMs get involved with uh devices on
the edge. I saw the other day this toy
for children.
>> Oh jeez.
>> That that it's like
help help your kids socialize by having
it talk to this robot.
>> Oh my god. uh is is not, you know, I
know this isn't a a parenting uh podcast
here, but I think we could all give uh
some uh advice on why that's not a great
idea.
>> Yeah. Jeez. Wow.
>> But in that case, now in that case, it's
moving back to the phase one model where
I'm sure what that's doing is it's got
some API keys on it and it's uh sending
your voice input. Maybe it's doing, you
know, voice to text on the device, but
then it's shipping that to the back end.
But I'm thinking how close are we to
where they'll want to bring that locally
on the device and run kind of like a
local LLM on devices and then you're
going to have you know prompt injection
on hardware uh things like that where
where those kind of bugs I I haven't I
haven't seen a bug like that yet but I
just think that if we look at what
happened in the ML space with with
trying to bring ML to the edge to do
like object object object detection,
things like that. I think you're going
to probably see that in the LLM space
also.
>> Yeah, I uh I had this exact
desire this morning. I got a Tesla
update to my Model Y last night and when
I got in my car today and I've wanted
this for a while, it said like Grock can
now control your navigation in your car.
So, they've exposed and it was like in
beta and so they've exposed some tool
call in in like Grock on Tesla that that
can now like control things in the car.
And so like I've been looking for this
exact moment to start looking for bugs
in this because before the Grock and the
Teslas was just the chatbot like it was
just and it had no personalization and I
still don't think it has any
personalization. But anyways, I couldn't
get it to work. Like literally Grock
wouldn't respond all morning in my car.
So I'm kind of annoyed because I wanted
to test this exact thing, right? It's
like yeah, you're right. There are going
to be
>> prompt injection in physical hardware
devices and um and yeah, I think that
toys right now could have a Raspberry Pi
in them that can run small models. There
are some like really small models like
GMO 1B and stuff that could totally have
like baby conversation like you know
it's not going to be good. It's not
going to be able to tell you any
legitimately useful information about
the world but it can say hi and how are
you and it can imitate uh Elsa or
whatever right.
>> Oh my god. Our kids are going to start
saying certainly you're right.
>> Oh yeah.
>> Hi dad.
>> Yeah. Like yeah it's going to turn them
totally sickopantic or whatever like
these models. Oh my gosh dude. That's
terrifying. That's freaking terrifying.
>> Yeah.
>> Um wow. Well, yeah, I definitely think
that makes sense. You know, if you've
seen the trend with ML, um it it'll
probably also hit that with AI. I'm
trying to think about, you know, attack
vectors for that. I mean, there could be
um you know, MCP server built into the
device where it's trigger triggering
tool calls and stuff like that. Um and
you know, maybe you're speaking to it
and you know, you say, "Hey, do this."
And it does it. Um so that that
certainly seems interesting. Uh, but I
think it's just another way to interface
with the device in large capacity. So,
um, I think it might I'm trying to think
about like how how would I actually
convert this into like, you know, an
actual reasonable vulnerability besides
business logic. And I'm like, I guess I
could say apostrophe semicolon, you
know, and it's like if it's piping into
a command line, you know, you could do
it, but I think it'd be pretty
challenging to do that verbally.
>> Well,
thought into this and I've always
thought that you would basically record
a payload. So you would work a lot with
your own device. You'd have a recorded
payload and so and you would also play
play it like sub what's the word where
like humans can't hear it.
>> Oh yeah. I don't know the word but
>> anyways there's a word for that like you
would so you would play it below what
humans could play or you would play it
with certain tones that are out of the
human range. So, you could still play it
loud, but it would be like really high
pitched or really low pitched or
something and you would pre-record it.
And so, then when you get in the car
with someone's Tesla, you would play it
and it would then it would automatically
do that thing, right?
>> Oh [__] dude. That's crazy.
>> That's the way you pull it off. Or have
you seen this? Matt would probably know
way more about this than me. There's
like things like called like directional
speakers. Um, oh, actually, I think you
can transmit audio to input uh mics via
like infrared, too, or something. I've
seen like
>> You can do it with lasers. So,
>> lasers.
Yes, you go ahead. No, you know more
about me.
>> Yeah. Yeah. So, Sammy Camcar, his work
is what you'd want to look into. Uh
YouTube, Defcon, everything. Uh so, he
found that he could use a laser and uh
you know, send audio with a laser
microphone through a window and activate
an Amazon Alexa device
and speak. you could record it,
translate it into whatever his laser
input is, and then shoot it through a
window towards someone's Amazon Alexa
device to like trigger a uh what's it
called? Oh, actually, yeah, I recently
heard this is I'm not going to mention
the the company. There was a AI
vulnerability that was reported where
you could start a call with somebody
that and it would open up the audio. So,
you could essentially enable their audio
via a prompt. And so, if you could put
that through this laser thing through
the camera, you could basically turn on
a mic in their house that you could
listen to. Holy, dude.
>> That's crazy.
>> That's the full chain,
>> dude. How did people come up with this
[__] with the lasers and like Oh my
gosh.
Jeez.
>> That's a good question. I don't even
understand how audio works to know how
it would go through a laser.
>> Yeah, that a lot of physics uh physics
stuff there. Yeah,
>> for sure. Let's um let's I'm sorry, we
we got a little distracted with the AI
uh IoT um dreaming here. Let's circle
back around. Um, uh, Joseph, did you
want to go into some of this, uh, like
attacking how these robots would, you
know, how we would go after these robots
or did you have a different, um,
>> so I do want to get to Matt Brown's IoT
hackbot and Matt Brown zero to hero
guide, but yeah, that was actually one
of my questions and I don't even think I
put it in the doc, but it's like the
main point of the episode like that I
wanted to know personally. It's like
Matt Brown, we've delivered you a Unit
Tree robot or a Boston Dynamics robot
because honestly me and Justin would
love to uh get one of these in alpha or
beta
>> to both test on and because it'd be so
fun to have one when they're probably
going to be like 50k when they come out.
Yeah. You know, Tesla drops you a new
humanoid robot. What would be like, you
know, give us the first eight hours of
you like basically pin testing this
thing. You know, what what does that
look like?
>> Oh, wow.
>> This is great.
>> Yeah. Yeah. So, any device like that,
uh, there's there's going to be a a
reconnaissance phase, right? Uh, it's
it's a little bit simpler with consumerf
facing electronics, uh, because you can
you can get a lot of information off the
FCC. Uh, if if if if it transmits
wirelessly and it's sold in the United
States, uh, then by law, they have to
report certain details about like the
inner workings of the device and post it
on the FCC's website. And there's a
third party website that searches that
information way better called FCCI
FCCID.io.
And so, uh, basic reconnaissance.
Honestly, nowadays Grock for all of my
hardware recon. I'll like put in like,
hey, here's here's the target. If I know
anything any other details about uh
about the device, I'll say, "Hey, you
know, like look into all the
subcomponents that I know about at the
time and give me any, you know, known
CVE, any kind of past research blog
posts." And so I just kind of send Grock
out to be like, "Hey, deep search, you
know, turn turn on deep search, send it
out." Um,
>> and then I'll let that run while I start
opening up the device. And so I'm going
to open up the device. I'm going to
gather more uh data about what chips I
see inside of it. Probably like, you
know, add that into the gro flow. Um but
then are you using Grock as like your
primary AI for this? Because I I hear
that like I don't hear that that fair
very often. I'm mostly hearing people
using like Gemini or Claude. So, so I
use Claude for all tool calling stuff,
but I I just use Grock because it
doesn't it doesn't take up my my Claude
tokens. Uh when I'm doing like light
light internet search recon stuff. Uh so
like that's literally just in the web
browser. Uh all my other AI like hacking
flows now are are quad cloud-based.
>> I think that's smart. I did the same
thing, Justin. I don't know if I've
mentioned it much, but like if I have a
random question that I expect would be
enhanced by web results and just other
users, like the stuff in the past, you
know, you used to Google like something
something something Reddit because you
wanted like the public opinion about the
thing. Now I use Grock for that because
it's going to like be looking at all
those tweets that are kind of relevant
and then it also does a pretty good job
of searching online and it's also really
fast.
>> Um, so I also do that for like when I
want a quick answer about stuff that I
want public opinion about and public
documentation about.
>> That's interesting. I I'll often use
Gemini for that, but I'll I'll have to
check out Grock and I use Gro a little
bit on mobile because it's like right
built right into the X app and I can
just be like, you know, but um yeah, I
I'll have to give that a go and see how
it how it performs. Um okay, so swinging
back around to that, you're you're
performing recon on the device. You kick
off an agent to go do some uh FCC um
recon. You're opening up the device. Um
and then I guess it kind of depends on
what you see there. I mean, uh, do you
have do you have thoughts on like how
you think that that might be implemented
in the future or are we just going to
have to wait and see?
>> Oh, yeah. So, for the for the robotics
tech,
>> um, no, one of those hardware
assessments would be so fun because it's
going to be a little more complex most
likely than
>> your average IoT device where there's
one processor. It might be a
microcontroller. It might be a CPU like
running Linux or Android, but your
average device, there's like one
processor, maybe some some flash
storage, some external flash storage, uh
maybe there's a debug connector, but in
these more complex systems, there's
often times, you know, circuitry.
There's often like multiple PCBs. It
might be in different parts of the
robot. So you might have to like take
apart the head and that's like the
camera unit and take apart the body and
that's like the motor control uh
processor units and so uh then what the
cool thing about those systems where
there are multiple uh kind of PCBs or
components they have to talk to each
other somehow. So that's where you can
use a logic analyzer to start to read
those digital signals. You're you're bas
it's basically a physical uh you can
visualize it as wire shark at the
physical level. You're physically
looking at the electrical signals that
are going back and forth between these
different subsystems of a robot like
that and trying to see, you know, how
they work, right? Like like when the CPU
wants to send like a message to the arm
that says like move up, it's going to uh
send some kind of a digital signal. And
so you you can play with those a little
bit. uh that's not a vulnerability in
and of itself because it's like okay you
need physical access to the thing. Um
but in any in any hardware assessment
I'm looking for two large components and
that is debug interfaces and those vary
based on uh what your target is but a
debug interface is something that the
developer uses to develop on the target
right it's a developer tool that maybe
gets them access to log data maybe it
gets them access to a shell maybe on a
microcontroller unit it lets them upload
code and and and download code. And so
seeing if any of those debug interfaces
are enabled is uh step one.
>> That's going to be UART, right? JTAG or
like do you often see something like
where you can just hook it up, hook up
to it via like USB and like uh is that
something you also see or
>> Yeah, you see that especially on uh
Android devices. you you'll you'll see
USB interfaces and sometimes they'll be
like on the circuit board but there
won't be like a USB header uh you know
soldered up to it. So sometimes uh all
you all you have to do is like take a
USB cord, cut it, and then you got the
four wires inside.
>> So badass dude.
>> And so you've got power, ground, and
then you've got your signal plus your
plus and minus for your signal. and you
just it's four used to be is four wires
and you got you know you maybe do some
in your reconnaissance you look at the
data sheet you say okay I think this is
where I solder onto and now you've got
your USB hooked up again
>> I I haven't I haven't ever done any of
this with with USB before but how how
does that differ from like UART in this
scenario because my my my thing you know
my UART adapter that I've got sounds
very similar to what you just described
there
>> yeah so it it is um it's similar and
it's So USB I like I think we all like
understand at a at a high level that USB
does different things, right? Uh you
know on my computer I have a bunch of
USB ports, but those aren't just like
>> giving me shells on on on my computer,
right? That would be a pretty bad threat
model for like a PC to be to be just
like, oh, I plug in, I get a shell. Um,
so there it could be a a a just a hub,
right, where where you can like maybe
maybe you can connect in a device and
then the operating system can choose to
use that device uh kind like your PC or
it could be an interface for say ADB. So
on Android targets if uh if the if the
uh ADB is enabled then if you get a USB
connection to it you can then on your PC
that you've connected up this USB this
newly populated USB interface you can
type you know ADB devices and it will
enumerate over that USB interface if it
if it can connect to a device you can
say ADB shell and then if again if it's
enabled drops you to a shell
>> that'd be beautiful.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. So I guess on these on these just
one one last thing on that and then I'll
let you you take it Joseph. Um you know
on these sort of
>> I guess more robotic oriented devices
have you seen a trend one way or the
other between these three sort of debug
interfaces UR JTAG or or USB.
>> So on on on robotic devices there's
almost like I mentioned how there's
going to be multiple PCBs. There's
probably going to be both.
>> So, there's probably going to be because
if you think of uh
>> anything that's doing uh onboard ML or
or AI, it's going to most likely be
running Linux. The I the most popular
platform I've seen out there is the
Nvidia Jetson platform. So uh Nvidia
makes this embedded
GPU that is not as power hungry as their
you know as their kind of data center or
or or desktop models obviously. So that
can and then they provide a an SDK that
has an entire build system. So they
provide for you the Linux build system
and it actually has a lot of security
stuff built in. It's got some secure
boot built in. Uh you you can implement
that wrong. So, I've I've seen that
sometimes,
>> but
>> it broke. It's going to be a Linux
system, but then maybe but that's going
to do like all of the AI stuff, but then
maybe there's a another like processor
that's doing the motor control, right?
And so that is more likely those motor
control circuits are more likely to be a
microcontroller target. and
microcontrollers are going to more
likely have JTAG or SWD which is ARM's
version of J-tag. Uh whereas the Linux
side you're going to be looking for
UART.
>> Okay, that makes sense. So overall
likely it's going to have for the more
complex robotic pieces it's going to
have a micro computer core, right? So
we're running Linux uh probably this
Nvidia here. Um and then we might have
microcontrollers throughout the system
that are controlling various pieces of
it and kind of calling back up via these
you know hub here or this um uh you know
area where you could do hit it with the
logic analyzer um back up to the to the
microcomput core. Right.
>> Exactly. And those signals are usually
UART like serial signals also. So that
that those there there's there's a
couple different protocols. There's
there's UART there's I squed C. We don't
need to get into all there's SPI there's
different protocols that use you know
digital signals to you know commun do
interchip communication so
>> and and you and you can uh identify
those via the logic analyzer when you
hook up and you sort of uh pull off
those connections.
>> Exactly. So the most common logic
analyzer out there s makes really good
products. Highly recommend them. And uh
it comes with this software that's
called Logic or Logic 2. And it has
these analyzers that you can you can
plug in an analyzer and you can see if
it decodes data properly or not. So you
kind of test your hypothesis.
>> Let me just add that to my Christmas
list real quickly here.
>> Yeah, no joke.
>> Yeah,
>> that's great.
>> Actually, yeah. So, I have lots of dumb
questions, but um one one specifically
is like how do you balance not breaking
hardware devices that you get shipped
like like when you were talking about
opening up this humanoid robot, I'm just
like thinking like if Tesla sent me I
don't know, one of their humanoid robots
and it was like a $50,000 device and you
know, you're telling me like, "Yeah,
just crack it open, you know, start like
soldering stuff onto the back of it."
I'm just like, "Oh my gosh, I'm going to
break this thing." How do I know? Like,
you know, how do you balance that?
>> That is a great question. And so on a
higher value target. So so to take a
step back
>> when I'm doing IoT pen testing or or a
bug bounty hunting, I always prefer to
have more than one device. Like ideally,
I would have two to three devices. And I
would have one device that is like,
okay, this is my destructive testing
target. I don't care if I brick it. I'm
going to be really rough with it. And
then I'll have like on the other side of
the spectrum, I'll have like the clean
device that I like I open up only if I
really have to to do very safe
operations. But on the hardware hacking
spectrum, when you gain experience, this
is why I always suggest for people to go
go to Goodwill, go buy some used routers
and like practice on those targets that
are like $20, not the, you know, $50,000
target. But after you've had some
experience, you know which operations
are risky or pretty safe. Now, obviously
anything you could make a mistake and I
I could I could do my safe operation on
a device and I could still break it if
I'm if I'm really unlucky that day.
>> Uh but interacting with UART, that's
going to be pretty safe. uh t like like
doing hot air and pulling a chip off,
which is kind of the the the other phase
is is doing firmware extraction on a
device. So, kind of my my two big
hardware hacking operations, it's debug,
look for debug interfaces. The other one
is do firmware extraction. And anytime
you have to do firmware extraction,
especially if you're physically pulling
the chip off the device, you're at risk
of messing stuff up.
>> You're hooked, dude. When you said two
to three, I I was like, man, this guy's
a boss. you know, like in the one,
excuse me, but in the one live, you
know, live hacking event that I did for
hardware, they um and you were there,
Matt, so I think you you got the same
thing, but like
>> they sent us a link and they said, "Hey,
you can buy three and we'll reimburse
you
>> and and they sent us the link to the
three to the threeack." So, I bought
three of the threeacks.
>> And they did. They reimbured me. I was
like, "Hey, you told me I could buy
three of these, you know, and and and
then I did buy three of these, you know,
and um and so I had nine devices and
dude, I burnt through like six or seven
of them with all of this."
>> Like I was just like frying it with the
gun, you know, with the hot air gun. And
so I was like, "Yeah, I mean, for me,
it's a minimum of five devices, I
think."
>> That's funny. Since we've mentioned uh
is a digital anal or logic analyzer a
physical device?
>> Yes. Yes, it is. It's a physical device.
Um,
you can buy the knockoffs on Amazon for
about $20. I'll get you guys some links
to throw in your show notes. So, there's
there's a $20 one that'll that'll more
or less get you what you need. You're
going to it it like it's going to have
an advertised uh sampling rate on it
that is uh is not true. Like, you're
never going to get that rate, but for
most of our hardware hacking stuff, not
going to matter. It'll be fine. Uh, and
then SY obviously is kind of the the
Cadillac of a logic analyzer. And they
have a new device out which is really
fun. Like this is just me nerding out,
but they have a device that combines a
logic analyzer and an oscilloscope. So,
uh, if you really need an oscilloscope
for any work you're doing
for sure, 100%. Like I'm using an
oscilloscope all the time. No.
>> Does a uh does a flipper come in handy
much at all?
Uh, so I the flipper has grown on me. So
I would say it's kind of a toy, but I
have used it, funny enough, I've used it
in hardware assessments. I actually
bought it for a pen test because I knew
I was going to need to do infrared. Uh,
it was I can say the general target. It
was a TV, like a smart TV. And some of
these smart TVs, the remotes will have
like undocumented commands that you can
send over infrared to the television.
And so I needed a way to kind of
programmatically
uh interact with that. So I was writing
custom so for that pentest I was like
writing custom flipper apps that would
that would send uh data over infrared.
So there it it's useful in some cases.
Uh there are some limitations to it and
they're currently developing a new one
that's going to be like a full-blown
Linux system basically that's going to
have a lot more capabilities, but I
would say
it's it's kind of a toy is is how I
usually use it.
>> Yeah. Go ahead, Justin. You were gonna
say something.
>> Yeah. Well, I was just gonna I was going
to ask before about about something
else, but we can jump into um the
hardware hacking zero to her hardware
hacking guide because I think you had
some thoughts on some questions on
exactly, you know, how to proceed with
that and I think we've covered it up to
a good point here. You know, we've
covered it up to reconnaissance. Um and
so we're looking for debug interfaces
via UART, JTAG, uh USB, that sort of
thing. And then the other side of that
is is um firmware extraction. Before we
jump over to firmware extraction, did
you have anything else on on like the
the debug interface side? Tips and
tricks for identifying those or or tools
we might need to to be able to identify
those and hook up to them.
>> Um, no, I don't have anything else. I I
would like to go back if we're going to
the zero and hero. I'd like to jump up
to that kind of philosophy first and
then I can jump down into that cuz this
is something I get this question a lot
and
>> sometimes you can get stuck into the
weeds of the hardware hacking and so I
like to clarify for people what like the
goal usually is of our hardware hacking.
So to start that there there are such
things as hardware vulnerabilities like
like flaws that are baked into the
silicon. Uh these are these are oftent
times unfixable flaws but like like like
the fix is to like make a design and
fabricate a new chip is is usually the
fix for a hardware flaw like that. So
what I find is typically not technically
a hardware flaw. It's software flaws in
hardware devices. And so
>> I say that because usually all this
hardware hacking stuff, my philosophy is
a means to an end of hacking on software
and it's a means to the end of turning
what is like a blackbox assessment
because think about like you you get a
device and you can like maybe it had
maybe it has like an Ethernet port on
it. You you like plug it into your
network. You're like uh I could run like
end mapap on it. I could start like you
could treat it like a network pen test
and that would be blackbox right maybe
there's a web app on it and you could
treat it like a blackbox web pen test
but the thing that hardware hacking gets
us in that threat model in that scenario
is that it turns a blackbox assessment
into a graybox assessment. It gives us
more intelligence on how the device
works on the inside. Dude, frick. That
is such a beautiful point and it makes
it so much more approachable, right?
From, you know, from a from a a software
hacker's perspective, right? If I'm if
I'm working on my web stuff and I'm
thinking, oh, you know, hardware stuff
that's like so like the soldering and
the blah blah, right? You know, all of
that is just a way to get you source
code. And once you get source code, you
know, you're like, ah,
>> this is this is where I live, you know?
And and then it goes back to those those
comfortable skills of source code
review, of web hacking, and and of
course there are things like, you know,
Bluetooth or like like you're mentioning
all these UDP protocols that, you know,
web hackers in particular aren't super
comfortable with, but at the end of the
day, it's just a different skill set of
of um of software hacking, right? Um and
that makes it a lot more approachable. I
really I really like that clarification.
That's that's great.
>> Yeah. So then so then Yeah. And then I
kind of break down my my process again
into those two categories. There's debug
interfaces. So, and so so the debug
interfaces again on this kind of uh this
map of we're trying to get more
information. We're trying to get our
hooks into the device so we can hack on
the software so we can find a software
flaw in the device. the debug interfaces
they they they get like if we can get a
shell on a Linux device, right?
>> In in the context of turning it into a
graybox assessment, we can we can just
like we can view the process the the
running processes on the system. We can
uh like look at those processes that
have sockets open, right? So, so then we
can start to connect the dots to say
like, okay, before I was performing this
blackbox assessment and I saw this open
port, like maybe there's a web
application running on this IoT device,
right? Well, and you're asking, well,
where is the code for that, right? If I
can run netstat and I can see, okay,
port 80 is being opened by this process
named web, you know, like like there's
some binary that is listening on that
port. Now I know exactly where to go in
the firmware or on the device. Uh and I
can cuz cuz cuz when you when you look
at firmware, you're looking at like a
million files. You're like, what do I
look at first? And so those debug
interfaces often tell us exactly uh
where to look on the device.
>> That's beautiful, man. It's like it's
like if you have a shell on a server,
how much easier would it be to hack
that, you know? Like it's it's it's
beautiful. And especially when the
attack surface is so um so rich like it
is on a lot of these IoT devices, right?
There's there's um you know there's some
something happening over here over HTTP.
There's something happening over here
over like there's some weird UDP
protocol or like you know there's so
there's a lot of attack vectors in in
these sort of scenarios typically. Um
Bluetooth stuff, right? All that's
really fun. So
>> it feels like there like three things
you're doing by
>> by hardware probing. you're like getting
access to scope you didn't have access
to before. Like you can test things that
you weren't able to test. You can reduce
friction, which I think is what Justin
loves to say all the time around testing
things by being able to test them in a
more like automatable fashion or in like
a more repeatable fashion.
>> Um,
>> oh man, what was the third one?
>> Yeah, but it sounds like those are like
the main things, right? Is that you're
one able to get access to scope other
people can't or reduce the friction that
it takes to test these tough things to
test.
>> Yeah,
>> totally. Yeah. Okay. So, so we've we've
gone down that route. We we we've tried
to identify some debug interfaces. How
often do you think there are no debug
interfaces or like maybe the the um they
burnt these or something, right? Like I
I I've heard in the past like what'll
happen is they'll they'll like um you
know break the fuses or whatever on on
those specific lines.
>> Yeah. Yeah. So there there can be cases
where the debug interf I mean frankly on
most bug bounty targets because bug
bounty targets tend to be more secure
than the the nonbug bounty targets
generally I mean obviously that's not
always the case uh but especially in the
hardware world because there's not as
many hardware programs as there are uh
web programs so tend to be a little bit
more uh a hardened device where they
take security seriously and so yeah
oftent times you're going to be left
with maybe no debug interfaces or you're
going to be left with like a UR
connection that doesn't let you send any
data, but you might you might get some
data out, right? Like maybe you'll get
like standard out standard error of like
a of some programs running on the system
or maybe you'll get the kernel logs
during boot up or or or maybe it'll just
be blank and you won't get anything.
>> So, uh then the next step is firmware
extraction because uh with firmware
extraction, we can usually get some of
the firmware hopefully out of the
device. And so, uh, that's where we're
going to turn to look at those those
flash chips that are on the device. And
this does become kind of a game of
pattern recognition of, okay, so like I
I can now look at a PCB and I can see a
certain shape of a chip and I'm like,
that's the flash chip right there.
Obviously, uh, when you're new, when
you're new, you're you you're probably
going to have to read the little uh
serial numbers, little model numbers
that are written on the chip. do some
googling and you're like, you Google it
and you're like, "Nope, that's the CPU."
You Google it. Nope, that's nope, that's
the DRAM. And then you're like, "Oh,
here this is like, you know, flash like
EM EMC flash chip or or a spy flash
chip, something like that."
>> So, what are what are some uh you know,
I knew eMMC, but I didn't know the
second one. You said spy flash chip.
>> Yeah. So, there's Well, okay. So, so
technically that's the protocol that uh
the chip is speaking. So those come in a
lot of different packages. So in the in
the hardware world, a package just is is
the name for the physical dimensions of
the chip. So you're probably familiar
with eMMC. It's a larger uh square to
rectangular chip. And uh they actually
come in a lot of different dimensions.
And so sometimes you need like different
little uh cutouts to to to place that
chip into your programmer to read the
read the firmware out. Uh but there's
also, you know, little eightpin chips
that uh and and especially on cheaper
devices, you're you're more likely or or
cheaper or lower power or, you know,
lower budget devices that you're just
going to find those those kind of flash
chips. And so there's some that are like
called a TS a TSOP 48. I could I could
rip off all the names then that wouldn't
be too helpful for everybody. Uh but
there's it's a little uh you know chip
with you know 48 pins uh you know 24
each side. And so
uh those are those are some common ones
you'll find. But oftent times if you're
not familiar with it the the the
solution the easy path is just look at
the model number that's written on the
chip. Google all of the things that are
written on the chip and you'll you'll
probably figure it out
>> and eventually you'll figure it out.
Okay.
>> Yeah. So once you have detached it, how
do you then actually like view the
firmware?
>> Exactly. So this is where different uh
firmware reading tools are going to come
in handy. So the most universal
universal programmer that I recommend
all the time is called the XGU XCU.
Uh that platform is a device that has a
lot of different sockets that will fit
lots of different types and shapes of
chips into them. And they have profiles
for many many different types of flash
chips that you can read. You can read
eMMC flash chips now with the with the
uh the the better models of this uh
firmware reader and all all the way down
to the really uh lowbudget chips. And
so, uh, there's a piece of software, the
official one runs on Windows. There is a
open source project called Mini Mini Pro
that tries to give you, uh, some some
open- source options to interface with
the reader. It works sometimes. So, I've
resorted to having a burner laptop that
sits over here that doesn't have access
to anything else on my network because
it runs this Chinese .exe that uh that
you probably don't want just like on the
rest of your network. So uh you run this
software, it interfaces with the with
the flash reader. You place the flash
chip in a socket. There's many different
sockets that you can buy uh to fit all
the different kind of chips into the
reader. And then you click a button and
it says here's the here's a a binary
file with all the firmware.
>> Yeah. And then what do you do with the
binary file in order to like actually
make sense of it?
>> Dude. Okay. Hold on. Hold on. Hold on.
Before we go down that route, like I
just got to just give the listener the
beauty of that moment.
>> Like guys, you don't understand the
moment when you take this flash chip and
you put it in your thing and and it
reads it successfully, guys. Like it is
just
it is one of my favorite moments that
I've ever had in in hacking is that
moment when it when I and it was crazy
because it's not even really the
hacking, right? It's just like, you
know, just getting it to I feel like I
just plugged a, you know, micro USB chip
into my computer. But like the fact that
now I'm staring at the, you know, the
file system of this thing that I'm
trying to hack, I just feel so much like
like potential, you know, and and hope
for how I'm going to like destroy this
device. Um, so really beautiful there. I
did want to jump back before we we go
into what we do with that binary. Um,
you know, when you are removing these
chips, I see in your notes here you you
have your gun set to 800 or to 850
Fahrenheit. I feel like that's freaking
hot. Is that not like super hot?
>> That's probably hotter than most people
would recommend, but uh
>> Yeah. Is there a reason why you do that
or
>> I'm impatient? Uh
well that makes me feel a little bit
better cuz like you know Joel you know
Joel my co-host um you know for the
first couple years was yelling at me one
time cuz I was like trying to it's funny
cuz we were working together on this
event and for some reason he did not
have the device. I forget and maybe he
was like a plus one that event or
something like that but I was like hey
man you know guide me how to hack this
right and and I'm like setting the air
gun he's like no don't put the air gun
that that high or else you're going to
fry the chip. And I'm like, "Oh shit."
You know, like and I'm like, you know,
trying to undo it. And um but it was
only at like 450 or like 500. And I was
like, "Let me just eat, you know, he
would look the other way and I would
like ease it up a little bit because it
it takes a while to to burn off the, you
know, the solder that holds it holds it
there."
>> Yeah. Especially with those larger chips
like you were dealing with an eMMC chip.
So the kind of kind of the most standard
package for an eMMC chip is 153 solder
balls that are underneath that chip.
It's just a large surface area. Also
depending on the device like you know
underneath of it and or or on the size
of this chip there's often times these
massive heat shields these large metal
components that are going to soak up
>> the heat that you're just I mean you're
just you're just blowing heat
indiscriminately. I mean, you're trying
to you're trying to aim it at the chip,
but obviously these large metal surfaces
are going to absorb a bunch of that
heat. And so on those targets, sometimes
I'll go and I'll try to like rip off all
the shields before I do something like
that just because it'll be less heat for
the uh to be absorbed elsewhere.
>> Totally. Totally. That makes sense.
Okay. So, sorry. Going back to your
question, Joseph, um we we've extracted
the binary, we've we've got the firmware
image. What's your go-to uh strategy
from there, Matt?
>> Yeah, so Binwok is is definitely the the
go-to tool for extracting firmware. So
the you run binwokase
e and that will attempt to just go
through this large binary file because
like you said, you don't get handed a a
a partition table out of the firmware
file, right? You don't get handed all
these individual partitions. I mean
sometimes you can do it with eMMC but
usually you have to like already know
the partition table so it doesn't really
help you. Uh so when you get that one
large binary file so let's say it's like
a 16 gig you know eMMC chip you just get
a 16 gig file that has all of the file
systems the partitions
crammed into one file. And so what
binwalk will do is it will try to
signature detect you know hey I see an
ext4 Linux file system here let me let
me let me carve that out and try to
unpack the file system. Now sometimes
binwalk will fail on you. So this goes
back to uh kind of the debug interfaces.
oftent times if you do get a a boot
print out on UART oftent times on a
Linux system it will uh in the boot logs
of like when the kernel is starting up
it will show you like a readout of the
partition table and all of the offsets.
So sometimes if binwalk is is just
sometimes it's like not able to detect
or it's got a really weird file system
uh on in one of those partitions you can
often times go and get all of the
offsets from the UR printout and then
you can basically more or less convert
that into DD commands uh using DD to uh
you know carve out the exact bytes at
the exact offsets for each partitions
and then you can try to use other tools
from there. Uh, more kind of like
standard tools to unpack certain file
systems.
>> Check the magic bites on those or
whatever, you know, and and make sure
you've got your your stuff aligned
properly and then pull it all out.
>> Exactly.
>> That's cool, man. That's freaking cool.
I I I've seen those readouts before and
but I never correlated that with with
like, oh wow, if my my binwalk is having
some issues, then I can I can use that.
So, that's that's a really cool tip. Um,
>> sweet. And then from there you all would
do things like look for secrets, find
routes, see what types of um source code
you can get for both the device and any
web apps and just like do traditional
open source code review at that point,
right?
>> Yeah. And and most of the time, so
sometimes uh you get lucky and you'll
get source code on your IoT device, but
most of the time it's going to be
binaries. That's why I say we're we're
we're going from blackbox to gray box.
it's not completely open cuz often times
uh you you'll see like if you see a web
app on an IoT device most of the time
it's going to be written in C and it's
going to be a compiled uh server where
the web server and web application are
like custom and they're like all one.
>> Wow. And so uh there's a lot of uh so
that's where you get into binary reverse
engineering with tools like gedra binary
ninja IDA pro things like that. How how
often are you able to get those binaries
back to something more readable than you
know like assembly you know like like
sometimes there's compiled Python
sometimes there's you know some CGI you
know stuff going on you know what what
often do you see what stacks
>> yeah so I think we're in a much better
position so when I when I kind of
started my career you know 10 10 15
years ago or whatever. We had IDA Pro
which you had to pay you have to pay out
the nose for. It's expensive. Uh and
that was it. Since then uh the NSA open-
sourced GEDra and so uh Gedra's
decompiler is very effective. Uh and now
we also have binary ninja that has
entered to market. So we have we we
don't have like this monopoly in the
software uh binary reverse engineering
kind of tool space anymore which is
really great. it's spurred competition,
uh, which is always good for the market.
So, we've got a lot we've got a lot of
good tools that will get you back to
more or less what the original C looked
like. Again, oftent times these programs
are are going to be C, C++. Uh,
sometimes you'll find you'll find you'll
find some Python uh, in there,
>> but really like 90% of the time or more
it's going to be C.
>> Yep, exactly.
>> Dang it. Dang it, man. Oh, that hurts.
That hurts, man. I really have gotten
lucky because I it's twice now that I
have dealt with um you know IoT devices
that are not straight uh you know
straight C I you know and so my my
experience is is so like you know uh
flowery you know it's like oh great and
then I pop it open and just decompile
this Python or like pop this jar into
you know Jad X or whatever right and
it's like okay but it's not it's not
normally that way I guess. No. And and
and if I had to like give my meta
analysis of that, I would say that bug
bounty targets tend to be on some
devices that I would say are more or
less like overspeced or overbuilt. So
they have more powerful CPUs or
resources on those systems and therefore
>> they can afford to run Python which is
not as efficient as C or C++. So, but on
on a lot of like low power, low resource
devices, you're probably not going to
find Python.
>> Dang, man. Dang. That sucks. Well, I I
uh I so enjoyed my my little stint there
in the Python code review land, but
that's not what I can expect from most
IoT devices. It doesn't seem
>> unfortunately. No. I I wish I wish that
was the case.
>> Yeah.
>> Sweet. And then so we have uh Matt
graciously gave us like a list of like
six links. There's an intro playlist by
Make Me Hack for getting into hardware
hacking. There's a post about URPI. And
then there's a bunch of links to Matt's
videos about UR interaction and firmware
extraction that we will put in the show
notes and the hacker notes for everyone.
>> That should be great. Yeah, those are
always good reviews. And then did you
want to jump from there, Joseph? Over to
IoT. I'm not going to let us I'm not
going to let us hang up today. I'm not
going to let us get off here without
talking about this IoT hackbot. So,
>> okay.
>> Yeah. So, Matt, we heard that you built
an IoT hackbot. Basically, a agent that
helps you hack. So, tell us the full
story. You know what, you know, what is
it? How did you build it? You have a
video about it.
>> Well, I was shooting some ideas over to
here and uh I was telling him about some
about some stuff I was doing. So, it was
originally just using cursor. I I I have
to say I'm a late adopter to all of the
LLM stuff. I was m maybe in the
skeptical camp at first. Uh so, I'll
I'll admit that. I'll admit that here on
the pod, but uh I've started to see the
value. So, I originally started by
wanting to build some very specific
tools. So where this started, I was uh
doing some security research on some IoT
cameras and I wanted to build some
attack tools that were very specifically
targeted to these set of cameras. So in
the security camera world, there's a
standard called ONVIF, which is a
standard set of APIs that uses SOAP and
XML, and it's gross and I hate I hate
SOAP. And so I'm like, you know what? an
LLM could probably code me a tool in
Python that'll make me not have to like,
you know, uh blow my brains out because
I'm like writing all this like XML stuff
into my into my Python tool to to do
checks. So, uh so it all it all started
that way with with writing this tool. So
in ONVIF there's a there's a set of APIs
that are defined in the standard and
some are pre-author that you can execute
without authentication and then
everything else should require
authentication. So I wrote this tool to
go through every API in the spec and to
try to see if I can access it without
authentication. So it requires a
different uh SOAP, you know, XML payload
for each one, which would just I mean
that that would have just been pure a
pain to try to do that. But um yeah, but
but but uh the LLM was able to just go,
oh yeah, I'll go read the spec and I'll
write a Python tool that will that will
execute that. And I found some bugs. And
so this got me started on this journey
of okay what if I could you know build
some kind of agents or stuff like that
and that's when I reached out to you and
you were like hey you should you should
use cloud code and on the same day it
just so happened that that was like it
was on the same day that uh Claude
released their skills and so that uh
it's it's with which claude skills are
um I mean it's it I don't know if it's
an overhyped feature but it's really
helped me and So, uh, cloud skills are
basically a markdown file where it
doesn't read in the whole markdown file
into the context window, uh, where you
can tell it how to use certain tools.
So, I started out by, okay, I had these
two little tools for testing these IP
cameras. And so, I was like, all right,
let's create Claude skills for those,
and then I could just let Claude Code
use them. and it basically one-shot, you
know, this camera and and was able to
find like a bunch of and then I even
posted a video of how I was able to tell
it to like write a payload. Uh so in the
ONVIF spec for PTZ cameras, which are uh
pan, tilt, zoom cameras that can
actually move physically on their own.
Uh and I had a camera that supported
that. I was able to tell Claude to go
and you know like like enumerate like
like like find if there's any vans and
I'm like and if there's a vaugh I mean I
knew there was a vaugh but if there's a
van you know move the camera and so uh
it was able to you know find the APIs
that didn't have off and then use those
APIs to move to physically move the
camera.
>> How crazy is that man? You're just like,
"Move the camera." And then you wait and
all of a sudden it goes and you're like,
"Oh my gosh."
>> I mean, that's the closest thing to like
in a movie where it's like, you know,
like computer,
>> computer, hack this device and make it
move. Like, give me a better view of the
angle. And the the computer runs off and
it's like, I'm going to use Matt Brown's
skill to go hack this and then I'm going
to turn the device, right? It's like it
achieves the outcome.
>> It's like Riley from National Treasure,
right? You know, the that was like when
I was younger, that was my like hacker
inspiration was like the dude from
National Treasure that was like, "All
right, I I'll turn off the security
cameras, you know." Um, wow, that's
actually Matt Brown's like Tuesday, you
know?
>> Yeah. The reason why I recommended
Claude Code, just for all the listeners,
is it's just such a malleable
agentic um rapper, you know, like I
think that that's what's so powerful
about it. I think they're building it
that way on purpose. You know, like
Daniel Measler uses it for his like
personal assistant and he gives like all
the context about his projects and his
businesses and a bunch of skills and he
used it for that, right? In this case,
Matt Brown basically made a hackbot out
of cloud code. And it's so much easier
and better to do that for most people
than to build it from scratch, right?
Because you're you're writing all of
that wrapper logic anytime you're going
to build an agentic system. But you can
just like borrow the agentic wrapper or
the agentic harness from claude code and
then just give it the ability to do the
things you want to do and for $100 a
month you basically have like written
your own custom agent right to that's
actually like really good and will
always improve as they improve their
system prompts as they improve their
models as they improve the tool calling.
And so anyway that's why I recommended
that to Matt and I think you know for
99% of use cases that's the best thing
you can do. Um, obviously with like with
Kaido, Justin and I incorporated Shift
deeply into it because it needs to have
access to all of the different things
that Kaido can do. And so, you know, I
think that's the next step for a lot of
things. But if you have a desire or a
goal to achieve with some sort of AI
agent, I think the first thing that most
people should do is PC it by like
totally, you know, just giving skills to
cloud code.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. And that was such a good
suggestion cuz I think I linked to you
one of the open-source agent, you know,
you know, pentesting uh or security
testing agent systems. I'm like, "Oh,
yeah. I'm thinking about doing this."
And you're like, "H you should just use
cloud code." I'm like, "That was that
was a that was a good move." I would
have gone way too far down the rabbit
hole that did not need to go uh did not
need to be explored at that time. So
>> it's it's amazing, man. I actually in
instead of using cloud code, I'm
actually using Gemini CLI and and after
hearing more about cloud code, I'm not
sure that that's 100% the best, you
know, decision, but I am sort of living
in that ecosystem a bit right now. So,
um I I think I'm going to stick with it
for the time being. I have seen in Shift
that Claude is way better at tool
calling.
>> Uh you know, so that that is definitely
goes to Claude. Um but I I had a similar
situation where um you know I kind of
give it a you know obscure protocol that
that is just horrible to write and I say
like look just map this to like a JSON
file for me please and then write you
know write a Python file to map it back
to to whatever like garbage you know
this is and it did it and it totally
changed the game for hacking that target
because you just reduce so much friction
in creating your payloads and and uh you
know h how much more thorough can you be
when you're not like spending an hour on
one, you know, API endpoint crafting
the, you know, XML you need, right?
Versus like, you know, you might get two
through two or three of those before
you're like, ah, they probably all have
O, you know, versus like if you if you
can just spin them out, you're like, oh,
well, I'll just test all of them really
quick and then you find that, you know,
second to last one that is like doesn't
have O and gives you a shell.
>> So,
>> yeah, it's unlocking a new scope and
then reducing friction. Those same two
things, right?
>> Yeah. Exactly. and and and and I love
the ability of Claude. Yeah. The
reversing binary like like like binary
protocols or some undocumented protocol.
So that was the other cool video I did
on this same video camera. So uh did one
you know did one where we found all of
the the the
phones in the protocol that was
documented that that followed this
specification this open specification.
There was also this UDP port uh that had
this completely undocumented protocol
and that led me to develop these other
skills and one of them was the ability
to interact with my hardware hacking
tools. So my UR interface that I had
hooked up to this camera that in this
case was able to give me a root shell. I
wrote a cloud skill for piccom, which is
just one of the Linux utilities that's a
terminal emulator that allows you to
interface with the device. So now I can
give Claude code a shell on an IoT
device and it can run commands to
enumerate the system just like I would
do uh in a pentest. And this was really
important for in this in this video for
reversing a binary protocol because
helpfully the main binary uh that that
was running this binary protocol would
send logs to standard out that would
appear on the console. And so it was
able to, you know, craft a script, run
an exploit over the network so that the
device is connected over the network, it
can talk to it over the network and it
would had a shell on the device and so
it could it could get that feedback
because as a security researcher, that's
the flow I that's what I would do,
right?
>> Totally.
>> Is I would craft PC scripts. I would
send a payload uh to a service and then
I would try to get any kind of
intelligence on the device like is there
is there something going to a log file
that I can see an error message uh that
will help me fix my my PC my my exploit
that I'm
>> yeah I think I think that this is very
similar to I think this is just an
overarching principle for LM like a lot
of people they just want them to work
because you see you know the magic of of
cursor or whatever, right? But I think a
lot of stuff that's a little bit more
nuanced like this and I'm finding this
out with shift and you you've seen this
with your own, you know, Claude Hackbot
is making sure that they have the right
tools and the right information, right?
Because our brains sort of fill in the
details. I'll give an example from this
like I because by the time this um talk
this pod airs my naman talk will already
have run but um one of the things I'm
talking about in that is how uh like
shift agents which is essentially the
web version of this right with inside of
Kaido they get so much more effective
when you give them things like the
session token in an environment variable
right that it they it can sub in very
easily um or additional pieces of
context surrounding that right so if you
if
And a lot of times, you know, as humans,
if we look at the session token, we can
say, "Okay, that one starts with 983 or
whatever. That's this user. Well, the
other one's got to be the other user
then, right?" But if you can, you know,
define this for the LLM, spell it out a
little bit easier. Give them tools to
make this stuff a lot a lot quicker, the
performance just like goes through the
roof. So, building that that tool,
right, for you to get access to to
standard um standard out and and or
standard error here and like watch these
logs, I mean, that's that's got to be
the gamechanging move. uh for the for
this whole thing and then it was able to
completely based off of those logs and
with the Python script it would just
reverse it and it gave you something
that can speak that protocol.
>> Exactly. Yeah. And the one other piece
that is a future improvement. So the
other piece I was giving it also was
decompiled source code that I I had
copied and pasted out of my out of
binary ninja. So the next piece for me
is to do MCP to those tools. Yeah. So,
uh I'm exploring different options.
GEDra obviously has uh you know GRA MCP
uh there there's some limitations of
that. I think you you have to like
manually open the binary. You can't have
it like programmatically load a binary.
>> At least that's my understanding at this
point. So, I'm looking at some different
options. I know that I know that Caleb
Graass um an operator has done some
really interesting research on reverse
engineering and then using LLMs to like
identify uh you know specific pieces of
the code that like he he did it
specifically with patch diffs right so
you can say okay hey you know here's the
CV here's the description here is a
patch diff you know in you know the of
the binaries right what function is the
one that fixes the patch and where the
vulnerability was you know and then he's
got it nailed down to like the top like
4% of all the functions that can be like
okay this is the one you know that are
that is related to this. Um so I think
you know being able to use something
like that I know he's got a tool called
SIFT um that can help you really sort of
narrow down okay well these are the
pieces of functionality that we're
really interested in for uh the specific
piece of functionality um and then pass
that to the AI seems to get
substantially better results.
That's awesome. I need Yeah, I need to
check that out.
>> Yeah, we'll I'll uh I'll hook you up
with him after this after this pod. Um
yeah, Joseph, I think we've hit a lot of
the items here on our list. Did you have
uh have something else here?
>> No, I'm Yeah, all of my uh questions
have been asked. All of my answers have
been found. Um no, I'm excited to to
mess with this stuff more. I think that
honestly I'm going to have some sort of
like hardware arc in 2026. Uh that
that'll be the goal. Dude, you you and
me together, man. I was thinking I was
talking to Matt. We'll see. We'll see.
Maybe maybe we'll put this in the pot or
not, but it would be really awesome to
do a um opponent to own team, you know,
uh together, you know, and if next time
they they release like their their
target list, just pick one and then, you
know, have have Matt do some of the
hardware stuff, have us go, you know,
find out the vulnerabilities in this in
the software stack once we've got access
to source code or whatever. Um or, you
know, gray box, right? decompiled
binaries as it always ends up.
>> Um, I think that could be a blast.
>> Yeah, that'd be slick.
>> Yeah. All right, Matt. Well, thank you
so much for coming on the pod, man. It
has been very insightful as always. And,
uh, yeah, definitely going to do some
hardware hacking with you this upcoming
year if we can.
>> Sweet.
>> Can't wait.
>> See you, dude.
>> That's a pod. Bye.
>> And that's a wrap on this episode of
Critical Thinking. Thanks so much for
watching to the end, y'all. If you want
more critical thinking content, uh, or
if you want to support the show, head
over to ctbb.show/isord.
You can hop in the community. There's
lots of great highlevel hacking
discussion happening there on top of
master classes, hackalongs, exclusive
content, and a full-time hunters guild.
If you're a full-time hunter, it's a
great time. Trust me. All right, I'll
see you there.